<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contribution Guidelines on MongoDB C&#43;&#43; Driver Manual</title>
    <link>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contribution Guidelines on MongoDB C&#43;&#43; Driver Manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 16:11:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mongocxx.org/contributing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing the legacy driver</title>
      <link>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/legacy-release-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 16:11:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/legacy-release-guide/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, chances are you&amp;rsquo;re about to issue a release for a new version of the legacy C++ driver. Congratulations!
Before Getting Started To perform the release process, you will need the following:
 git, python, doxygen installed on your local machine. Push access to the mongodb/mongo-cxx-driver repository on GitHub. Push access to the 10gen/apidocs repository on GitHub. Administrative access on the C++ Driver JIRA project.  This guide assumes that you have a local clone of the mongo-cxx-driver and apidocs repositories, and that your GitHub remote is configured with remote name origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing the mongocxx driver</title>
      <link>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/mongocxx-release-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 16:11:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/mongocxx-release-guide/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: To follow these instructions, be very careful which branch you&amp;rsquo;re working on:
 Version bump/tag/post-bump commits go on the branch corresponding to the release. Documentation updates go on the master branch.  The instructions below will remind you about branches.
Update fixVersion Status in Jira tickets  Ensure that all tickets under the version to be released are in &amp;lsquo;Closed&amp;rsquo; status on the C++ Driver roadmap page If not, bulk change Open tickets that will NOT be in the release to a new version (create it if necessary):  Audit Jira ticket titles and types for use in release notes  From the roadmap page click the &amp;ldquo;Release Notes&amp;rdquo; link to see a summary of tickets to be included in release notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the legacy driver</title>
      <link>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/testing-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 16:11:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/testing-legacy/</guid>
      <description>If you contribute to the C++ driver, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to test your changes. The driver comes with a number of tests to ensure its functionality and performance. There are a few different kinds of tests within the driver&amp;rsquo;s codebase.
Note: if you are running OS X Mavericks or above, you may need to include the --osx-version-min=10.9 flag to the commands below.
Note: The 26compat branch differs from the instructions below as follows: * MongoOrchestration is not required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the mongocxx driver</title>
      <link>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/testing-mongocxx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 16:11:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mongocxx.org/contributing/testing-mongocxx/</guid>
      <description>Tests for the C++11 driver use Catch, a testing framework for C++.
Each class in the driver has a corresponding file in src/mongocxx/test. Because the new driver wraps libmongoc, we prefer to mock and test the behavior of individual classes rather than test end-to-end behavior of operations against a running mongod. In other words, these are unit tests rather than integration tests.
We also have integration tests for this driver in test/collection.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>